Last updated: July 11, 2017

Toran Sahu

Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys

B. Tech (CSE) NIT, Raipur

toran.sahu@yahoo.com, toransahooooo@gmail.com +91 8602431733

Summary

2 Years of total work experience at Infosys Ltd.

Currently working as Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys Ltd for IT projects in PLM domain. Responsible for understanding the business requirement, designing, implementing & delivering the solution as being the first point of contact for the client.

Have experienced many technologies during corporate projects - Oracle database, PL/SQL, Java, .Net, C#, Python, Siemens Interspec/Meridian and Selerant's DevEX PLM.

Good understanding of data structures, database, algorithms, and business understanding coupled with sharp analytical and problem-solving skill.

Actively want to switch company as a full-time software engineering role. Looking for a challenging work as well as fun. Want to be around professionals to learn as much as possible.

Experience

Senior Systems Engineer at Infosys

July 2017 to Present

Systems Engineer at Infosys

June 2015 to June 2017

Contributed in two data migration projects.

Requirement gathering, discussion. Solution designing and Implementation. Solution deployment and maintenance. Client interaction.

Database extraction, transformation & migration from Meridian to specific templates using PL/SQL in the production environment. And then retirement of old data from Meridian's database.

Console application development for automation of supportive tasks using Java/C#.

Technologies Experienced: Oracle 10/11g, PL/SQL, Java, C#

Projects

ProConf - Meridian Data Migration- Mondelez International

October 2016 to Present

ProConf project is about migration of some plants related data from its database to Selerant

PLM's database, as those plants were going to separate from MDLZ. It requires deep understating of oracle database and its integrity with the Meridian. The whole project includes 4 major parts: Extraction, Transformation, Migration & Retirement.

Meridian is PLM web application for process Industries to develop, configure and manage all product specifications (e.g. raw materials, intermediate and finished Products, packaging materials).

toran.sahu@yahoo.com 1

Last updated: July 11, 2017

Responsibility: Managed the project single handedly

Technologies Used: PL/SQL, Java and C#.

Meridian Retirement – Kraft Foods

December 2015 to September 2016

Meridian Retirement project was to migrate the whole data from Meridian's database to Oracle Agile PLM's database, as Kraft Foods was going to merge with Heinz Company. It requires deep understating of oracle database and its integrity with the Meridian. The whole project included 4 major parts: Extraction, Transformation, Migration & Retirement.

Meridian is PLM web application for process Industries to develop, configure and manage all product specifications (e.g. raw materials, intermediate and finished Products, packaging materials).

Responsibility: PL/SQL and console application programming

Technologies Used: PL/SQL, Java and C#.

MS Excel Implementation of Regression Clustering

January 2015 to April 2015

An Application Software for attribute prediction of the data present in Excel file with minimal error estimation using regression clustering.

Technologies Used: Java2, MySQL, WEKA API, Apache POI

Data Fragmentation for given Cluster Centers

July 2014 to December 2014

An Application Software for fragmentation of the data present in Excel file according to given cluster centers.

Technologies Used: Java2, MySQL

Library Management System

January 2013 to March 2013

An Application Software made in Java2 to manage the college library system.

Technologies Used: Java2, MySQL

Honors and Awards

Insta Award

Infosys Limited, Mar 2017

Certification awarded in appreciation of exceeding the client's expectations for the works assigned.

Insta Award

Infosys Limited, July 2016

Certification awarded in appreciation of quickly learning INTERSPEC tool, helping the team to build database queries & extraction process, hard-working, and dedicated nature.

Skills & Expertise

Python, Java, C, C#, Git, Linux, PL/SQL, SQL, NoSQL, Data Structures, Algorithm, HTML, MVC, PLM Tools

toran.sahu@yahoo.com 2

Last updated: July 11, 2017

Education

National Institute of Technology Raipur Bachelor of Technology (B. Tech.), Computer Science & Engineering, 2011 - 2015

Grade: 6.96/10

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Malhar, Bilaspur (C.G.), 2010

12th, PCM, 2009 - 2010

Grade: 72%

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Malhar, Bilaspur (C.G.), 2008

10th, 2007 - 2008 Grade: 83.4%

3 toran.sahu@yahoo.com